College English Test, Band 6,
Part 2, Listening Comprehension.
Section A, Directions.
In this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
centre. Conversation 1.
Charles, as a singer, do you ever make yourself cry when you sing?
No, not at this stage.
I'm an old man.
But the songs can still get through to me.
What songwriters are currently exciting you?
I don't know much about songwriters.
Once in a while, I'll listen to the radio to see what they're putting out.
But it's not too often I hear something I like.
Somebody like Art Tatum can make me sit up and take notice.
But some music, like rap, isn't very musical and I can't learn anything from it.
You've to do something more than talk to me.
What's the most difficult kind of music to sing?
It depends. If I like something, I can sing it.
I did the opera Porgy and Bess, and that's said to be a complicated piece of music.
And I can do country music, blues and love songs.
On the other hand, I can't sing something I don't like, and that's one of my
defects. Can you perform music that's out of tune with the mood you might be in on a
given night? Yes, because when you sing, you're like an actor performing a part.
Once you get out there, you become that part.
Only you're using music instead of dialogue.
I'm the kind of a person that if my personal life is hurting, I can go to work and
the music will take over.
It's like a guy who goes to a bar and drinks.
For those few hours, I can wrap myself up in my music.
Questions one to four are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question one. What does Charles say songs can do when he sings them?
Question two. What does Charles say about himself as a singer?
Question three. singer?
five. singer? Question six.
Question three. What's one of the man's weaknesses?
Question four. What will Charles do when his personal life is hurting?
Conversation two. wonder if you could tell me a little bit about your job as a radio
announcer. What do you actually do and how do you prepare for your job?
Well, in the newsroom, I'm sitting with the reporters and the news subs as though
I'm sitting in a newspaper newsroom.
Sorry, what do you mean by news subs?
They're sub -editors.
They're the people who write the news stories as they come in.
The stories are then passed to the senior duty editor and the assistant editor.
As stories go through the chain of people, they're refined, corrected and sorted out
until they come finally to me and I have a chance to read through most stories
before I go on the air.
Of course, sometimes things happen at the last moment and I don't have a chance.
So I've just got to do my best and take a couple of seconds to look through the
first few lines before I launch into something.
Because it's such a pity if you start off on a bright tone on a story and suddenly
realise you're talking about some people having been killed in a road crash, it's
very important to just have a quick flip through.
There's nothing to what sort of event it is on your piece of paper.
No, I have my own little mark.
If it's something sad, I put a small cross at the top.
That's my little clue.
So while I'm working on the news, I'm just absorbing the news and checking
pronunciations. What does the woman want to know about the man?
Question 6 What does the man say new subs do?
Question 7 What does the man say is a big challenge for him?
Question 8 What role does the man say his small cross plays?
Question role does plays?
Section B Directions In this section you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. sheer numbers provide any proof, America's universities are the envy of the
world. For all their troubles, the United States 3,500 institutions were flooded
with more than half a million students from 193 countries last year.
Asia let the way with the biggest number from China followed by Japan and India.
Most European and Asian universities provide an elite service to a small number of
people. While fully 60 of all US high school graduates attend college at some point
in their life, just 30 of the comparable German population,
28 of the French, 20 of the British and 37
of the Japanese proceed beyond high school.
Britons who pass their A levels may still not qualify for a top university at home
but find American universities far more welcoming.
Some US schools acknowledge the rigor of European secondary training and will give
up to a year's credit to foreigners who have passed their high school exams.
The conception that everyone has a right to an education appropriate to his
potential is a highly democratic and compassionate standard, says Marvin Bresler, a
professor at Princeton University.
True, not all US students can match the performance of their foreign counterparts
but American institutions do offer students from rich and poor families alike the
chance to realize their full potential.
America educates so many more people at university that one can't expect all those
who go to be as intelligent as the much narrower band in British universities, says
Professor Christopher Ricks at Boston University.
I'm not against elitism but I happen to like having people who are more eager to
learn. Questions 9 to 11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9 What does the speaker say about America's universities?
Question 10 What is Americans' view on education according to Professor Marvin
Bresler? Question 11 What do we learn from Professor Christopher Ricks' remark?
Passage 2 Every year people in America use energy equal to over 30 million barrels
of oil each day.
That's energy in all forms oil, gas, coal, nuclear, solar and even wind power.
Viewed from a scientist's standpoint all of the energy contained in fuel either now
or in the future becomes heat.
Some of the heat is used directly or produces useful work.
The rest is lost or rejected radiated into the atmosphere from the engines, motors,
boilers and all the other energy consuming machinery that makes America's wheels go
around. If we could figure out how to improve the efficiency with which we use
energy we could do a lot more work with the energy that is available.
With money and careful planning we can boost efficiency up to a point yet
improvement won't come easily It won't come overnight and there are limits beyond
which not even science can take us.
According to the Center for Strategic and International Studies about three quarters
of the energy we use to move things including ourselves accomplishes no useful work.
In terms of efficiency and cleanliness buses, trains and other forms of public or
mass transportation are superior to the private automobile but only if they operate
at near capacity otherwise their overall efficiency is poor.
For some people mass transit may answer all transportation needs for others a
combination of mass transit and private transportation may be desirable.
Better design and wiser use of both mass transit systems and private vehicles will
play an important part in helping America get more out of energy used for
transportation. Questions 12 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
What does the speaker say about energy used in the United States?
Question 13 What do scientists say about energy contained in fuel?
Question 14 When does mass transit prove superior to private vehicles?
Question 15 What seems to be the speaker's biggest concern?
Section C Do directions?
this section you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks followed by three
or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a
single line through the center.
Recording 1 Hello,
and gentlemen. It is my honor to introduce our keynote speaker for today's lecture
Gretchen Rubin. Ms.
Rubin received international attention for her 2009 best -selling book The Happiness
Project in which she reexamines her own happiness and tries to develop mood
-boosting habits. Today Rubin will share with us her mood -boosting experience.
Welcome, Ms. Rubin.
Good afternoon, everyone.
Before I elaborate I'd like to first brief some of my most effective mood -boosting
tips. For the most part they can be accomplished in a minute or less.
1. Make your bed The thing that's surprising to me is that for most people outer
order does contribute to inner calm and creativity.
One easy way to maintain order and in turn boost happiness is to make the bed every
day. 2. Smell the roses or something else nice.
I used to laugh at scented candles but now I understand scents are a to get a quick
lift without any time, energy and money.
3. Follow the one -minute rule
Overwhelmed by unopened mail and other tiny tasks?
The one -minute rule says that anything I can do in less than a minute I should do
without delay so I don't postpone hanging up my coat printing out a document and
filing it glancing over a letter and throwing it away.
4. an alarm and not just for waking up Since sleep and mood are linked I think folks
who struggle with turning out the light may benefit from a bedtime alarm.
For many people an alarm really helps they just need that trigger.
5. Don't like a Stop reading it.
I mean I don't watch a TV show if I don't like it so why not apply the same logic to
books? I used to have this feeling that a real reader would finish a book if he
started it. Now I just have so much more time to read the books that I like and I
love everything that I read.
6. Take one thing with you This one may be especially helpful for parents When
leaving a pick up as you go one thing at a time without having to dedicate a lot of
time and energy to it.
to an upbeat song It's familiar but it actually does work it's a very easy way to
change your mood.
8. Jump up and down I strongly recommend this simple energy booster especially when
you may only have a few seconds to spare.
9. Kiss someone you
Ancient philosophers and contemporary scientists would agree that relationships are
a key may be the key to happiness so anytime you do something that broadens your
relationships or deepens your relationship it's going to make you happier.
Make some bright line rules I believe habits have a direct connection with happiness
and I think hard rules can spare one the agony of decision making.
Now I will explain these tips one by one in details.
16 to 18 are based on the recording you have just heard.
16 Which of the following is a mood boosting habit according to Ruben?
Question 17 What is one minute rule according to the lecturer?
Question 18 What does bright line rules refer to?
I would like to talk about interesting words that have something to do with money
today. Almost every language in the world has a saying that a person can never be
too rich. Americans like people in other countries always want more money.
One way they express this is by protesting that they're just Jobs do not pay enough.
A common expression is I am working for chicken feed.
It means working for very little money.
The expression probably began because seeds fed to chickens made people think of
small change. Small change means metal coins of not much value, like nickels which
are worth five cents.
An early use of the word chicken feed appeared in an American publication in 1930.
It told about a rich man and his son.
Word expert Mitford Matthews says it read
Chicken feed also has another interesting meaning known to history experts and World
War II spies and soldiers.
Spy expert Henry S.A.
Beckett writes that some German spies working in London during the war also worked
for the British.
The British government had to make the Germans believe their spies were working.
So British officials gave them mostly false information.
It was called chicken feed.
The same person who protests that he is working for chicken feed may also say I am
working for peanuts.
She means she is working for a small amount of money.
It is a very different meaning from the main one in the dictionary.
That meaning is small nuts that grow on a plant.
No one knows for sure how a word for something to eat also came to mean something
very small. But a peanut is a very small food.
The expression is an old one.
Word expert Mitford Matthews says that as early as 1854 an American publication used
the words peanut agitators.
That meant political trouble makers who did not have a of support.
Another reason for the saying about working for peanuts may be linked to elephants.
Think of how elephants are paid for their work in the circus.
They receive food, not money.
One of the foods they like best is peanuts.
When you add the word gallery to the word peanut, you have the name of an area in an
American theater. A gallery is a high seating area or balcony above the main floor.
The peanut gallery got its name because it is the part of the theater most distant
from where the show takes place.
So peanut gallery tickets usually cost less than other tickets.
People pay a small amount of money for them.
Questions 19 to 22.
Are based on the recording you have just heard.
19. What does a person can never be too rich mean according to the talk?
Question 20. What's a person's purpose of saying I am working for chicken feed?
Question 21. What can we learn about the German spies in World War II according to
the talk? Question 22.
What is the talk mainly about?
Recording 3. The family is changing in the US as in many other countries in the
world. About 50 years ago in in the traditional families the father was boss.
Now in a modern family both the father and the mother are equal partners.
There are some great differences between the traditional family and the modern
family. The first important difference is in the man's role.
The traditional husband was the head of the household because he was the only one
who worked outside the home.
If the wife worked for pay then the husband was not considered to be a good
provider. In many families today both husband and wife work for pay.
Therefore they share the role of head of household.
In addition the traditional husband usually made the big decisions about spending
money. However the modern husband shares these decisions with his working wife.
Also the traditional husband did not help his wife with the housework or meal
preparation. Dinner was ready when he came home.
In contrast the modern husband helps his working wife at home.
He may do some of the household jobs and it is not unusual for him to cook.
The second difference is in the woman's role.
In the traditional family the woman may have worked for pay during her first years
of marriage. However after she became pregnant she would usually give up her job.
Her primary role was to take care of her family.
In contrast in many families today the modern woman works outside the home even
after she has children.
She's doing two jobs instead of one so she is busier than the traditional mother
was. The traditional wife learned to live within her husband's income.
However the modern wife does not have to live within her husband's income because
the family has two incomes.
The final difference is in the role of the children.
In the traditional family the children were taken care of by the mother because she
did not work outside the home.
However today preschool children may go to a childcare center or to a babysitter
regularly because the mother works.
The school age children of a traditional family were more dependent.
Their mother was there to help them to get ready for school and to make their
breakfast. In contrast modern children are more independent.
They have to get up early in the morning and get ready for school.
Their mother is busy getting ready for work so they may even have to make their own
breakfast. In conclusion the American family today is quite different from the
family of 50 years ago.
In the modern family the roles of the father mother and children have changed as
more and more women work outside the home.
The next century may bring more important changes to the American family structure.
Questions 23 to 25 are based on the recording you have just heard.
23 Which of the following is the feature of a modern family?
Question 24 Why were the school age children of a traditional family more dependent?
Question 25 Why is the American family today so different from that of years ago?
This is the end of listening comprehension.